{
  "english": [
    {
      "id": 0,
      "questionNo": 1,
      "question": "What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
      "options": [
        "Original DOM",
        "Virtual DOM",
        "Both A and B.",
        "None of the above."
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "Virtual DOM"
    },
    {
      "id": 1,
      "questionNo": 2,
      "question": "React merges the object you provide into the current state using setState().",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "questionNo": 3,
      "question": "React.js was Initially released in................",
      "options": [
        "May 29,2013",
        "April 29,2013",
        "June 29,2013",
        "May 29,2014"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "May 29,2013"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "questionNo": 4,
      "question": " Which of the following is the correct data flow sequence of flux concept?",
      "options": [
        "Dispatcher->Action->Store->View",
        "Action->Dispatcher->View->Store",
        "Action->Dispatcher->Store->View",
        "Action->Store->Dispatcher->View"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "Action->Dispatcher->Store->View"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "questionNo": 5,
      "question": "React is used mainly for building ................",
      "options": [
        "Database",
        "User interface",
        "Connectivity",
        "Design platform",
        "code optimazation"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": [
        "User interface",
        "code optimazation"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "hindi": [
    {
      "id": 0,
      "questionNo": 1,
      "question": "निम्नलिखित में से क्या प्रदर्शन बढ़ाने के लिए React.js में उपयोग किया जाता है?",
      "options": [
        "मूल डोम",
        "वर्चुअल डोम",
        "A और B दोनों।",
        "इनमे से कोई भी नहीं।"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "वर्चुअल डोम"
    },
    {
      "id": 1,
      "questionNo": 2,
      "question": "रिएक्ट सेटस्टेट () का उपयोग करके आपके द्वारा प्रदान की जाने वाली वस्तु को वर्तमान स्थिति में मिला देता है।",
      "options": [
        "सत्य",
        "असत्य"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "सत्य"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "questionNo": 3,
      "question": "React.js को प्रारंभ में ................ में जारी किया गया था।",
      "options": [
        "मई 29,2013",
        "अप्रैल 29,2013",
        "29 जून,2013",
        "मई 29,2014"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "मई 29,2013"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "questionNo": 4,
      "question": "निम्नलिखित में से कौन फ्लक्स अवधारणा का सही डेटा प्रवाह अनुक्रम है?",
      "options": [
        "डिस्पैचर-> एक्शन-> स्टोर-> व्यू",
        "एक्शन-> डिस्पैचर-> व्यू-> स्टोर",
        "एक्शन-> डिस्पैचर-> स्टोर-> व्यू",
        "एक्शन-> स्टोर-> डिस्पैचर-> व्यू"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": "एक्शन-> डिस्पैचर-> स्टोर-> व्यू"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "questionNo": 5,
      "question": "रिएक्ट मुख्य रूप से निर्माण के लिए प्रयोग किया जाता है ................",
      "options": [
        "डेटाबेस",
        "यूजर इंटरफेस",
        "कनेक्टिविटी",
        "डिजाइन प्लेटफॉर्म",
        "कोड ऑप्टिमाइजेशन"
      ],
      "answerValue": [],
      "isAnswer": false,
      "answer": [
        "यूजर इंटरफेस",
        "कोड ऑप्टिमाइजेशन"
      ]
    }
  ]
}